# 四伯爷 今天弄条鱼给你吃
Uncle, I will make you a fish dish today.
# 要得
Sure!
# 就拿姜葱来给你煎
I'm using only ginger and green onions to cook the fish.
# 要得， 反正我干活儿还干累了
Yes! I am exhausted after working anyways.
# 你好生点整点好的来把我的身体补起来
You better cook something epic to compensate my body.
# 拖垮了还要不得
It would be bad if I drain myself for working too much.
# 就是这条鱼
This is the fish.
# 要得
Nice!
# 好生点哈 板下去了你在那儿（池塘里）去摸不到哈
Be careful. If it jumps back into the pond, you can never catch it again.
# 开玩笑 从我的手头板（逃）不脱
You are joking! It won't escape from my hands.
# 这鱼好瘦哦
This fish is so skinny.
# 这种鱼好吃点不是饲料鱼
This kind of fish is more delicious, since it's not fed with fodders.
# 对，就是这样
Yes, that's it!
(Slicing some ginger and green onions)
(Some lard)
# 在这个里面放点盐进去
First, we put some salt into the wok.
# 防止这个鱼粘锅
So the fish won't stick.
# 小点火哦 四伯爷
Uncle, can you turn down the fire?
# 这个鱼应该是你第一次吃
This should be your first time eating this kind of fish dish.
# 这个做法因为在川菜当中没得这个做法的
Because there's no such kind of recipe in our Sichuan Cuisine.
# 是啊
Yes
# 川菜中哪个拿猪油来做鱼嘛，都是用菜油
Nobody uses lard to cook fish in Sichuan Cuisine. Just rapeseed oil
# 这个是创新菜
This is an innovation!
# 好嘛 你就创新菜嘛看你又创什么新嘛
Fine. Let's see what you have for your innovation.
# 创出一个新世纪来
Create a new epoch.
# 新世纪倒不是反正是一个创新菜
This is too much... Just a little cooking innovation.
# 等这个鱼煎到另一面黄了再放点盐
When one side of the fish turns golden, we add some salt again.
# 然后再翻面这样就不会两面都粘得很厉害
Then we flip the fish, so it won't stick as much.
# 煎到这个时候把姜葱放进去慢慢炸
At this stage, we can put in ginger and green onions to be fried slowly.
# 可以啊
Sure.
# 才上得到味哒
That's how to absorb all the flavors.
# 然后这个时候火要小
At this stage, we have to make sure the stove is on low heat.
# 都烧得小
Low?
# 再烧小点都熄了
The fire is almost gone!
# 然后把这个锅盖盖上
We put the lid on.
# 让它慢慢的焖
Let it simmer slowly.
# 把鱼鳔一起丢进去慢慢煨
We can also put the swim bladders in.
# 趁这个时候来打一个汁
Now, let's make a seasoning sauce.
# 先放一点酱油
Some soy sauce.
# 再放一大半的料酒
Some more cooking wine.
# 料酒放了再放一点耗油
Then we add some oyster sauce.
# 耗油不能太多一点点就可以了
Don't put too much oyster sauce. A little bit is enough.
# 然后再放一大勺这个白糖
Then, we add in a big spoon of sugar.
# 待会儿提味道就是这个东西
We are going to use this sauce to season our fish.
# 这个菜名的话应该叫做姜葱焗鲤鱼
This dish should be called: Fried Carp with Ginger and Green Onions.
# 我看一下这个怎么样了
Let me see how it looks。
# 四伯爷这个火可以稍微大点了
Uncle, you can turn up the stove now.
# 好
Okay.
# 现在我们这个鱼两面已经煎香了，下面那个姜葱味也煎出来了
The flavor of the fish starts coming out, so as the gingers and green onions.
# 然后再翻它一下
Now, we flip the fish again.
# 你看 这一面也是金黄金黄的
See, golden!
# 四伯爷
Uncle,
# 你看哈嘛这个鱼煎到这个时候
at this moment,
# 就把这个搅拌均匀从边上淋下去
we pour in the seasoning sauce from the side.
# 那中间不淋啊
What about the middle?
# 中间要翻面的
Remember, We will flip the fish.
# 好 然后把锅盖盖起
Put on the lid.
# 这哈可以烧大点撒
Can I turn up the heat?
# 不要太大就是要小火
No, we just want low heat.
# 烧它过几分钟就可以了
Cook for another few minutes should be enough.
# 这个鱼不辣，吃起来这个肉还是比较嫩
This fish is not spicy, and the meat is tender.
# 姜葱味比较重鱼的鲜味都在里面得
It not only has the flavor of the fish, but also the flavors of gingers and green onions.
# 就跟白味差不多
Its like Bai Flavor in Sichuan Cuisine.
# 哦 好香哦
Oh! Smells good.
# 这个汁水把它淋上去
Pour the sauce on top of the fish.
# 现在这个时候鱼就不能翻了
We can no longer flip the fish at this moment.
# 我们这个筷子插这个鱼身上
We use this chopstick to poke the fish.
# 轻轻的插进去就说明这个鱼已经熟了
If it goes through easily, the fish is done.
# 准备起锅了
We are ready to serve.
# 四伯爷
Uncle.
# 来 动手
Let's try it.
# 欣赏哈看
Let's see.
# 尝哈看嘛这个鱼不辣
Try this fish. It's not spicy.
# 而且是姜葱把它慢慢焖出来的
It is slowly cooked with all the gingers and green onions flavors.
# 姜葱加猪油
Gingers, green onions, and lard.
# 为什么放猪油不放菜油呢
The reason we use lard instead of vegetable oil
# 这个就是猪油的吸附力更大，味道巴得更紧
is that lard can absorb more flavors. Therefore all the flavors can stay in the fish.
# 有味吧
Pretty good, right?
# 可以
Really nice.
# 嗯 好吃
So good.
# 嗯 这个味道是不一样
This actually tastes different.
# 真的吗
Really?
# 嗯
Yea.
# 这个鱼我是实验了大概10多次吧
It took me over 10 attempts for this fish recipe.
# 就是把它煎
We fry the fish first,
# 放油下去两面煎
fry both sides with lard.
# 把这个腥味去一下
This will remove the fishy smell.
# 煎好了之后再放姜葱下去
After that, we add in the ginger and green onions.
# 放到油里面慢慢炸
Let them slowly fry in the oil.
# 然后把锅盖盖起来
Then, we put on the lid,
# 把这个姜葱的香味进到鱼里面
making sure all that ginger and green onion flavors go into the fish.
# 最后调料汁
For the seasoning sauce,
# 放点这个酱油耗油还有料酒，还有白糖给它搅匀一下
we add some soy sauce, oyster sauce, some cooking wine, and sugar.
# 白糖稍微重一点点
We can add a generous amount of sugar.
# 搅匀了以后等姜葱熬香了再倒进去
We pour in the sauce after the flavors of ginger and green onions start coming out.
# 再把锅盖盖上焖一会儿就可以了
Then, we put on the lid again, cook for another few minutes, and the fish is done.
# 真的好吃 这样整起
This is so good.
# 吃撒 拈来吃撒
Eat, come and eat!